TOKYO DAIICHI BANK KUSATSU BRANCH
（东京第一银行草津分行）
TICKET NUMBER
（号码牌）
Customer with the ticket number 128, please come to window one.
128号客人 请前往一号柜台
Welcome.
让你久等了
Withdrawal? Please wait a moment.
提款吗？请稍等
Mr. Tsujimoto.
十本先生
I am very sorry, but…
非常抱歉
this transaction is denied.
我们没办法帮你提款
What do you mean?
请问什么意思？
I have my passbook and stamp.
存折和印章我都有
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Excuse me, sir…
很抱歉
But you are not Mr. Kenji Tsujimoto, right?
你不是十本健二先生吧？
Please wait!
-等等… -好痛…
May I help you?
能跟你聊聊吗？
Thank God!
太好了
He stole someone's bag and tried to use the passbook
他拿的存折和印章来自偷来的包包
and stamp inside to withdraw some money.
打算取出别人的现金
Ms. Hanasaki, because you were temporarily filling in for us,
花琦小姐 多亏你来支援工作
we were able to prevent a crime.
还预防了罪案的发生
Thank you very much.
真是谢谢你了
Not at all…
不客气
It was just a coincidence.
这只是巧合
How did you know that he was suspicious?
你是怎么发现那个人很可疑的？
Well…
这个嘛…
I thought he was acting strange the moment he came in.
从他进门的时候 我就觉得有些奇怪了
He kept on glancing around, and he looked nervous.
他一直四处张望 鬼鬼祟祟的
And he was sweating in an air-conditioned room.
明明是在冷气房里 却一直流汗
So I checked his name on the slip and the stamped form.
我留意到这点 就对比了一下 提款单和登记单上的名字
They didn't match.
发现笔迹有差异
Mr. Soma, please.
相马 请过来一下
So I had it examined.
就请相马查了一下
It's the gentleman over there.
是那边的那位男士
Okay.
好的
So that's how you found out that his bag was stolen.
于是你就发现这是偷来的包包？
That's right.
没错
How cool! It's an instinct as a teller.
好厉害 这就是出纳员的直觉吧？
I was excited because it's been a while since I've worked as a teller.
大概是很久没有做出纳员的工作了吧 我觉得干劲十足呢
Ms. Hanasaki is the best teller.
你真是出纳员的典范呢
Can I take a picture with you later?
我待会可以跟你合照吗？
I am not… How about in front of the logo?
我算哪根葱呢？ 在那边的标志前拍 好吗？
She's getting carried away.
完全得意忘形了呢
Mr. Soma, you did a great job too.
相马先生 你也很优秀啊
Yes?
什么？
You responded to Ms. Hanasaki quickly
多亏你立刻明白花琦小姐的意思
and contacted the customer right away.
及时联络了客户
No wonder you two are the famous pair from Branch Inspection.
真不愧是分行稽核班的名搭档啊
No, we are not.
-哪里…
Jinx.
别抄袭我
KUSATSU ONSEN
（草津温泉）
This sashimi is delicious.
这生鱼片很好吃
The konjac tastes great too.
这魔芋也别有风味
My expectations are rising for the stone-grilled beef hitsumabushi.
现在我对主菜石烤牛肉鳗鱼饭 充满了期待呢
Yes.
是啊
Coming here and not trying Joshu Wagyu is like drawing a dragon without its eyes.
来这里不吃上州和牛 就如同画龙不点睛
It would be unacceptable!
我绝对无法接受
Is it that important?
有那么夸张吗？
I can't wait.
我迫不及待要尝尝它的美味了
Visiting the branches and eating delicious local foods
果然走遍全国各地的分行 吃遍当地的美食
is the highlight of working as a branch inspector.
才是分行稽核员的最大乐趣
Exactly.
说得对
We solve and assist with tiny problems at individual branches,
我们忙着解决及指导分行的各种问题
but we get so much hate for doing our job.
却还要被人讨厌
We deserve this kind of treat.
这是我们应得的奖励
But this time, we made them happy.
但是这次他们也很满意啊
Don't get carried away.
别得意忘形
That was a rare case that might happen only once a year.
那种事件一年能不能有一回都难说
You are right.
确实
-Oh? -What?
-不好了 -怎么了？
It's Mr. Shibasaki.
是芝崎次长
Keep mum about the hot springs.
我们来温泉的事可要保密
Hanasaki speaking.
你好 我是花琦
Great job, Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦 你太厉害了
Well done! The branch manager just called me.
做得好啊 我接到分行经理的致谢电话了
I was just lucky.
我只是幸运而已啦
Where are you now? Are you on your way back?
你现在在哪？在回来的路上了吗？
It is already late,
现在很晚了
so I am thinking of staying at a business hotel near the station.
我就打算在车站前的商务旅馆住一晚
That's not good.
这可不太好
Why?
为什么呢？
If you stay the night, you can't make it here
你们要是在那过夜 不就赶不上明天一早
tomorrow morning.
回来这里了吗？
Tomorrow morning?
明天一早？
I can come before noon.
我们中午之前会回去
It has to be morning.
不行 必须是一大早
I am very busy. I'll explain tomorrow.
总之 我很忙 具体情况明天告诉你们
Do you understand? See you tomorrow morning.
拜托你们了 明早见哦
Mr. Shibasaki?
芝崎次长…
What is it?
怎么了？
He hung up.
他挂电话了
You must be joking.
不是吧？
He said he was busy.
他只说他很忙
What? He always says he is busy.
什么？他总是说他很忙啊
We have no other choice. Let's eat this and the hitsumabushi and go back.
但是没办法啊 把这些和鳗鱼饭吃了就回去吧
Oh, no… This is no good, Hanasaki.
不 不行啊 花琦
Huh?
怎么了？
We must leave here now, or we will miss the last train to Tokyo.
我们必须现在坐上往东京 的最后一班车 不然就来不及了
I mean right now.
应该说现在马上立刻
Thank you very much for waiting.
两位久等了
This is our specialty dish. Stone-grilled beef hitsumabushi.
这是本店的招牌菜 石烤牛肉鳗鱼饭
It looked so delicious.
那看起来好好吃喔
You should have said no to Shibasaki.
你应该拒绝芝崎次长的
It's not my fault.
这不是我的错
You always speak out when you shouldn't.
要你闭嘴的时候不闭嘴
How come you didn't speak out today?
这种时候怎么又那么听话了？
We must hurry.
我们得走快点了
I should have gotten it to go.
早知道就打包带走了
-Hurry up! -I know.
-快点… -知道了
Good morning.
早
I wanted to try that stone-grilled beef hitsumabushi.
真的好想试试那个石烤牛肉鳗鱼饭
It even appeared in my dream last night.
我连昨晚做梦都梦到了
Same here.
我也是
Good morning.
早安
-Good morning.
-早安
Hello, General Manager Shindo.
早安 真藤本经理
Hey.
喂
Executive Director.
是常务
Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常务
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR TSUYOSHI SHINDO
（常务执行董事 真藤毅）
Don't worry.
没关系
Ms. Hanasaki, you're always full of energy.
花琦 你总是那么精神奕奕啊
Thank you.
托你的福
I appreciate that you are doing the work that everyone despises.
感谢你坚持做着旁人讨厌的工作
Businesses succeed due to the work done by unsung heroes like you.
企业就是靠你这样的无名英雄 才能立足
-Don't you think so, Mr. Kodama? -Yes.
-对吧 儿玉？ -是的
I completely agree with Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常务说得对
SECRETARIAL OFFICE ASSISTANT GENERAL MANAGER NAOKI KODAMA
（秘书室次长 儿玉直树）
Thank you for your hard work.
真是辛苦你们了
-Thank you.
-不会
Keep it up.
继续加油
They both look very happy.
他们两个看起来春风得意啊
He was finally promoted to Executive Director.
他这次终于升上 常务执行董事的位子了嘛
Your promotion this time
你这次的晋升
is proof that President Serizawa views you as his successor.
是芹泽行长视你为接班人的证明
Thinking about that makes me…
一想到这个我就…
Don't rush to conclusions. We can't be sure of that.
别那么快下定论 这事还未定呢
Yes, we can! Your time has finally come, Mr. Shindo.
不 真藤时代的大幕已经拉开
Even General Manager… I mean Executive Director Shindo
真藤本部长他…不对 是真藤常务
is happy to be promoted.
他也对升迁感到很开心啊
Why not? All bankers want to be promoted.
当然啦 所有行员都想升迁
Mr. Soma.
相马
I don't think promotion is everything.
我不觉得升迁就是一切
Hey!
什么？
I'm not saying that because I'm bitter.
我不是因为没得晋升才这么说的哦
It is not bad to step aside from the fast-track to enjoy life at my own pace.
但这样从容地 享受自己的人生也不错啊
I know.
我明白…
What's with that look?
你那是什么眼神？
Don't look at me like that.
别用那种眼神看我
You should understand that I am your boss.
我可是你的上司啊
I know. You're--
我知道 你是…
Ouch!
好痛
I'm so sorry, Mr. Shibasaki.
对不起 芝崎次长
You're full of energy, Ms. Hanasaki.
你一大早就精力充沛呢 花琦
Good morning. Are you okay?
早 你没事吧？
I'm fine.
没事…
Are we going to Nihonbashi Branch for inspection today?
你今天要去日本桥分行稽核吗？
What happened?
发生了什么事？
A customer is saying that he is going to sue us.
有位客户闹着要告银行
What?
什么？
COMPENSATION
（提出诉讼）
CRIMINAL CHARGE
（刑事控告）
Sue the bank?
告银行？
An issue concerning investment trusts, huh.
是关于投资信托的纠纷吗？
-It sounds tough. -Hanasaki.
-这案子看起来挺棘手 -花琦
Yes?
是
-Don't get fired up. -Huh?
-不要干劲十足 -什么？
Every time you get fired up, does it ever work to our advantage? No.
你每次干劲十足的时候 都没起过什么作用
Maybe once.
总有过一次吧
Even if it did happen once, forget it. Listen, Hanasaki.
就算有那么一次 也不算是什么 听好了 花琦
Never…
不要…
Never say unnecessary things. Grin and bear it. Right?
不要说废话 逆来顺受 对吧？
Right. And the Nihonbashi Branch Manager belongs to the Shindo faction.
没错 还有 日本桥分行的经理是真藤派的
That's very daunting.
那还真让人泄气啊
NIHONBASHI BRANCH
（日本桥分行）
I am Soma from Branch Inspection.
我是分行稽核班的相马
I am Hanasaki.
我是花琦
Thank you for coming.
辛苦两位了
I never asked for help from Branch Inspection.
我可没寻求稽核班帮忙呢
Stop wasting my time.
别浪费我们的时间
My branch is number one in the nation for its performance.
我们分行的业绩可是全国第一
We are not like other branches.
和其他分行是不一样的
Am I right, Section Chief Nakamura?
对吧 中村课长？
Exactly right, Branch Manager.
没错 经理
But headquarters received a complaint threatening to take legal action.
但是本部收到了 关于起诉原因的投诉信函
How could he sue a big bank like us?
我们可是大银行啊
He is just trying to threaten us for money.
那肯定只是想威胁我们要钱而已
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I am sorry, but we will confirm the details.
非常抱歉 那么 我们现在就来确认一下情况
The person filing the claim is Mr. Hiroshi Morozumi,
提出诉讼的被害人是诸角产业的社长
the president of Morozumi Industry.
诸角博史先生
Six months ago, he purchased a 30-million yen investment trust
他半年前 在你们涉外课的北原有里的推荐下
with the advice of Ms. Yuri Kitahara from Public Relations.
以公司名义 购入了三千万日元的投资信托
Recently, he needed cash, so he redeemed the funds
最近由于急需资金提出解约
and saw that he had lost three million yen due to loss of principal.
因为投资信托的价格低于投资金额 亏了三百万日元
But Mr. Morozumi says that at the time of purchase,
但是诸角先生声称在购入时
he was promised no loss, and that the principal was guaranteed.
你们曾保证不会亏损 并且可以保全本金
That's just false accusation.
这只是无稽之谈
He is making accusations because he's angry about his loss.
他是不甘心亏损 才会借题发挥
However--
但是…
Investment trust is a financial product with chances of risks and returns.
本来投资信托 就是有得有失的金融商品
PRINCIPAL IS NOT GUARANTEED
（本金不可保全）
Bankers will never say that the principal is guaranteed.
银行职员不可保证说本金可以保全
Right, Mr. Nakamura?
对吧 中村课长？
That's exactly right.
说得没错
Oh right…
对了
Nit-picking of the branch is the job of a Branch Inspector.
你们分行稽核班的工作 是挑分行的毛病吧？
But we are working responsibly as bankers of Tokyo Daiichi Bank's
不过 我们身为东京第一银行 业绩第一的分行员工
number one branch.
是带着责任感在工作的
Don't make me waste time dealing with such a trivial company.
不要让我们 在这么一家小公司的事情上浪费时间
Trivial company?
小公司？
But he says that he will sue us.
但是对方说要提出诉讼
He can't be serious.
他们不可能真的告我们
We have nothing to be accused of.
我们没有犯下任何过错
These people get carried away because we give them time and attention.
再说 太把这种人当回事 他们会得寸进尺的
With all due respect--
请恕我直言…
I am sorry but may I talk to Ms. Kitahara, who was in charge of this client?
非常抱歉 能让我们跟负责人北原谈一谈吗？
Please.
拜托你了
Well, Mr. Nakamura.
中村课长
Bring Kitahara since the Branch Inspectors want to see her.
既然分行稽核班的两位想见北原 那就去叫她过来吧
Yes, sir.
好的
Time is precious.
时间可是很宝贵的
Make it quick.
你们两位请快点解决
Yes.
好
What's up with that damn Branch Manager?
这个狗屁分行经理算什么东西啊？
Idiot! You are too loud!
笨蛋 你太大声了啦
Sorry. I couldn't resist.
不好意思 不小心就说出来了
There it is again. You're always unable to resist.
不小心？那你真是常常不小心呢
Being rude to us is one thing,
先别说对我们的态度了
but it's so rude to call our customers "trivial."
说我们的顾客是“那种小公司” 也太失礼了吧？
Calm down. Don't get too worked up.
冷静 不要那么冲动
Aren't you angry after he talked to you that way?
他那样说你 难道你都不生气吗？
He has pride as the number one branch, you know.
没办法 人家可是有全国第一分行的骄人资本
Is it that great to become number one?
第一就那么了不起吗？
It's not easy to become the number one amongst 750 branches.
全国750间分行的第一名 可不是那么容易就做得到的
They deserve the recognition.
他们这个成绩值得被认同
But…
但是…
He's the one that produced results and made this branch number one.
而且把业绩做到第一名的 就是那位分行经理
So it's only natural that he's looked upon favorably by the top.
上面给予高评价也是理所当然的
-The results are-- -All that matters, right?
-业绩就是… -就是一切 对吧？
You're finally starting to understand the nature of the bank.
你也总算明白银行的本质了
I don't.
才不明白
I just memorized it.
我只不过是死背
I didn't tell him that the principal was guaranteed.
我没说过会担保本金
Do you have any idea why Mr. Morozumi thought you did?
那么 为什么诸角社长会说 你是那样说的？
I think he is telling a lie.
我觉得他在撒谎
I see.
原来如此
Have you talked to Morozumi Industry about this issue?
你和诸角产业谈过这件事吗？
Yes. He came to the branch last week.
有 他们上周来过接待室
I've lost three million yen.
我损失了三百万
How will you fix this?
你们怎么赔偿我？
MOROZUMI INDUSTRY HIROSHI MOROZUMI
（诸角产业室长 诸角博史）
It's working capital!
这可是营运资金啊
I am very sorry.
真的十分抱歉
But unlike a deposit, the investment trust
但是信托投资和存款不同
has specialists investing customer's money on stocks and bonds.
专家们会把顾客的资产 投资运用到股票和债卷中
Sometimes it goes well and offers profits,
顺利的时候是可以从中获取利益
but you redeemed it when there was a loss of principal--
但是这次诸角产业 在价格低于本金的时候解了约…
Wait a moment.
等一下
Remember what you said?
记得你说过的话吗？
You said I wouldn't lose money because
你说这商品是不会亏本的
the principal was guaranteed.
还说你们会担保本金
No.
没有啊
What?
什么？
I didn't say the principal was guaranteed.
我没有说过会担保本金
Give me a break!
开什么玩笑？
I see. So that's why he's saying that he'll sue us.
原来如此 所以对方才会提出诉讼
He may be thinking that
要说诉讼的话
we will make up for the loss if he says he'll sue us.
我想他们是觉得 我们会补偿亏本的部分
I don't think we should assume that.
我想 我们不应该妄下定论
Anyway, I didn't guarantee it.
不管怎样 总之 我没说过那种话
Branch Manager told me not to deal with him.
桥爪经理也已经叫我不必理睬对方了
-But… -Can I excuse myself?
-可是… -我可以走了吧？
I told you everything I know.
我没有别的话可说了
I will return to my work.
请让我回去继续工作
How rude.
真没礼貌
She seems to be on the same page as Mr. Hashizume.
感觉是和桥爪经理站在同一阵线的
Right.
是啊
She won't say anything further even if we ask her.
就算我们再问 也问不出什么吧？
I guess so.
的确
Let's go talk to Morozumi Industry.
那么 就去问问诸角产业吧
All right.
好吧
Where are you going?
你们打算去哪？
We're going to Morozumi Industry to confirm the facts.
我们打算去诸角产业确认事实
That's not necessary.
没那个必要
What?
什么？
As Kitahara said, we didn't tell him that we would guarantee the principal.
北原都说了 她没有说过会保证本金
That's all.
这就是事实
-But we have to confirm. -You don't have to.
-但是为了慎重起见… -没这个必要
A Branch Inspector's job is to solve issues within the branch.
稽核班的工作是要解决分行中的问题
Don't poke your nose in, or meddle
超出你们范围的事
with things that are not your business.
就不应该乱打听 更别说出手干预
Yes, sir.
是
Thank you very much for your cooperation today.
那我们今天就先告辞了
Okay.
好
Let's go. Come.
走了
Are you really sure it's okay?
真的没问题吗？
We have nothing to be accused of.
我们又没什么过错
There is no way he will sue us.
对方应该不会起诉的
If by any chance, he sues us…
万一被起诉的话
Mr. Hashizume,
那桥爪经理
you will disgrace Mr. Shindo, who has been supporting you.
你就会让 一直关照你的真藤常务蒙羞了
Do you understand?
明白了吗？
Yes, I do.
明白了
Yes. Goodbye.
好 我先挂了
She is an elite.
真优秀啊
She was a teller until a year ago.
一年前还是做出纳的
-The eggplant is delicious too. -Thank you.
-这茄子也很好吃 -谢谢
It's you again, Mr. Soma.
相马 你又来啦
Hi there.
打扰了
"Again"? Don't be rude to my regular customer.
什么叫“又来了”？ 他可是重要的老顾客
I have to come eat here at least three times a week.
叔叔的料理三天不吃 我就想得发慌
Mr. Soma, you are the best customer.
相马 你真的是最棒的顾客
Yeah!
赞啦
Stop acting like a couple in love.
别那样 你们又不是热恋中的情侣
I want you to bring someone you are in love with.
你也给我带个热恋中的情侣回来啊
You didn't bring that boyfriend you just broke up with?
你没带之前那个男朋友回来吗？
Mai, you had a boyfriend?
小舞 你有交往的对象了吗？
Yes. He was two years older and working at a ward office.
有啊 是个大她两岁的区政府公务员
Mr. Soma!
相马
How did you meet him?
怎么认识的？
Her friend at university knew him.
是她的大学朋友介绍的
That's enough.
别说了
Sounds like a nice man. Why did you get dumped again?
听起来是个好男人啊 怎么又被甩了呢？
I didn't get dumped. We just broke up.
不是被甩 是和平分手
I think that stubborn attitude of yours is what causes problems.
就是你这种强势固执最让我头疼
She might have said something to him "with all due respect."
她可能跟他说：“请恕我直言”
I had my reasons.
反正原因说不清啦
But Mai's dream is to be a wife of a banker.
不过 小舞的梦想 是成为银行职员的老婆嘛
That's right.
也对
Let me repeat. I've never dreamed of such a thing.
我已经说过几百遍了 我根本就没那样梦想过
Excuse me.
不好意思
Right away.
来了
I have to go home too.
我也差不多要走了
Mr. Soma, I want to ask you something.
相马 我有一点很在意
It's about Ms. Kitahara of the Nihonbashi Branch.
就是关于日本桥分行的那位北原
What about her?
北原怎么了？
I think she's lying.
我觉得她在撒谎
Lying?
撒谎？
I didn't tell him that the principal was guaranteed.
我没说过会担保本金
She was too composed.
我觉得她太过冷静了
She had a miscommunication with a customer
明明和顾客产生误会
and threatened to be sued.
还被起诉了
Isn't that strange?
你不觉得奇怪吗？
She may be a calm person by nature.
或许人家天生就是那么冷静的人啊
She had been working as a teller before she went into Public Relations.
北原在考取资格调到涉外课前 一直是个出纳员
And?
然后呢？
Something about her bothers me…
身为前任出纳员的我
as a former teller.
就是觉得不对劲
Is it a former teller's instinct?
原来是前任出纳员的直觉啊
Mr. Soma,
相马
why don't we go see Morozumi Industry tomorrow?
我们明天还是要去问问诸角产业吧？
No.
不要
But you'll go even if I say no, right?
就算我这么说 你还是会去的吧？
Yes.
是的
Morozumi Industry is a company that makes precision parts.
诸角产业好像是制作精密零件的吧？
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -你们好
Can I see Mr. Morozumi?
请问诸角社长在吗？
President, you have a visitor.
社长 有客人
May I help you?
请问你们是…
I am Soma of Tokyo Daiichi Bank Headquarters.
我是东京第一银行本部的相马
I am Hanasaki.
我是花琦
It is too late to see a person from headquarters.
太晚了吧 你们本部现在才派人来
Yes?
怎么了？
I had my lawyer file a petition just right now.
我刚刚已经请律师提交诉讼书了
What?
什么？
PLAINTIFF HIROSHI MOROZUMI
（原告：诸角博史）
DEFENDANT TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（被告：东京第一银行）
I am so sorry.
十分抱歉
I didn't think he would really sue us.
我没想到他真的会告我们
Executive Director Shindo had trusted you
因为你说不会有问题的
because you told us that everything was under control.
真藤常务才那么相信你
I am very sorry.
真的十分抱歉
He has no evidence, so even if that trivial company sues us
他没有证据 就算对银行提出诉讼
they won't be able to win--
那种小公司也赢不了…
I am not worrying about who will win or lose in court.
我担心的不是官司的输赢
If news gets out that Tokyo Daiichi Bank is being sued,
如果东京第一银行 被起诉的事情传开来
people may think that
一般老百姓就会认为
our bank did something worthy of being sued for.
我们银行是做了什么非法勾当
Even if it's only one person suing us, it will cause damage.
就算只有一个人提出诉讼 也会给银行造成伤害
It doesn't matter whether we are at fault or not.
我们有没有错根本不是重点
Yes, sir.
是
Someone has to take responsibility for this.
必须有个人出来承担责任
They really told me that the principal was guaranteed.
她真的有说过可以担保本金
I see.
是这样吗？
For you bankers,
对你们银行来说
three million yen may be a small amount of money.
三百万日元也许算不上什么
But for me,
但对我们而言
we are running on a shoestring.
那可是我们微薄的资金啊
I can't give up.
我不能就这样放弃
Excuse me.
请问
Was this contract the first time you handled business with Kitahara?
这次交易是你和北原的初次合作吗？
I've known her since she was a teller.
她还是出纳员的时候 我们就认识了
I see.
是吗？
That was why I trusted her without doubt.
所以我才那么轻易地相信了她
She said I wouldn't lose anything.
她说不会让我有损失
She advised me to buy it so earnestly.
还很热心地为我推荐商品
That's why I can't forgive her all the more.
所以我才更不能原谅她
I'm sure you won't believe me…
不过 你们是不会相信我的吧？
Is that a diary?
这是笔记本吗？
I take notes in here so that I won't forget important things.
我怕忘事 所以会把重要的事情记在上面
This is it.
有了
This is the day when she explained the investment to me.
这是她为我介绍商品的那天写的
Let me see it.
可以让我看看吗？
PERSON IN CHARGE - MS. KITAHARA INVESTMENT TRUST STOCKS, BONDS SPECIALIST
（负责人北原 投资信托 债卷）
PRINCIPAL GUARANTEED
（本金保证）
WITH NO LOSS
（无亏损）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NIHONBASHI BRANCH
（东京第一银行日本桥分行）
PETITION
（诉讼状）
Ms. Kitahara.
北原小姐
Are you sure you didn't tell him that the principal was guaranteed?
你确定你没说过可以保证本金？
You don't believe me?
你们是在怀疑我吗？
We didn't mean that.
我们不是这个意思
Mr. Morozumi showed us his diary.
诸角社长让我们看了他的笔记本
He could have written that down later.
那种东西可以事后随便写吧？
I don't think so.
我并不这么认为
Mr. Morozumi said that
诸角社长说过
he trusted you because he knew you when you were a teller.
因为是从出纳员时就认识了你 所以他才那么相信你
If you sold the investment trust by lying to him,
如果你撒了谎 骗他投资信托
that's an unforgivable thing to do as a banker.
那么 身为一个银行职员 这是不可原谅的
Stop it, Hanasaki.
花琦 你说得太过分了
You deceived the customer to improve your performance.
你为了提升自己的业绩 所以欺骗了客户
No!
不是的
That's not it.
不是这样的
You don't know anything.
你们什么都不懂
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
Ms. Kitahara!
北原小姐
Hanasaki, hurry up.
花琦 你快一点
What is this all about?
这是怎么回事？
No one has achieved the target!
没有一个人达到目标业绩
Public Relations!
涉外课
You think you can be number one like this?
你们这样还想拿到第一名吗？
I am terribly sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Such a pain…
你们啊
You guys are all useless!
全都这么没用
You created an unprecedented scandal of being sued by the customer.
被客户告上法庭 只会制造前所未有的丑闻
Can't you do anything other than cause me trouble?
你们就只会扯我后腿吗？
I made this branch number one.
我好不容易让这家分行成为第一名
But you ruined everything.
全被你们毁了
Are you garbage?
你们是废物吗？
Is this room a garbage box?
这里是垃圾箱吗？
Kitahara, pick it up.
北原 捡起来
All you'll find in the garbage box is garbage!
从垃圾箱捡出来的全都是废物
If you don't want to be garbage,
如果不想当废物
improve your performance.
就给我做出成绩来
Yes, sir!
-是
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
That Branch Manager is awful.
那个分行经理真是过分
I agree.
就是啊
When he speaks like that, no one can say anything because they're scared.
他说成那样 还有谁敢回嘴呢？
It was nothing but verbal violence.
那根本就是语言暴力
That was how he managed people and improved performance.
那就是他管理部下 提升业绩的办法
She may have been suffering too.
她可能也很痛苦吧？
Who?
谁？
Ms. Kitahara.
北原小姐
She got upset when you asked her
你质问她
if she lied to improve her performance.
说她是为了提高业绩的时候 她那么激动
You deceived the customer to improve your performance.
你为了提升自己的业绩 所以欺骗了客户
No!
不是的
That's not it.
不是这样的
You don't know anything.
你们什么都不懂
You're right.
确实
She probably got upset because she wanted to at least deny that claim.
她那么激动 是因为想要否定你说的话吧？
Do you need me, sir?
你找我吗？
Write a letter of resignation.
你…主动辞职吧
What?
什么？
Since we are being sued, someone has to take responsibility.
都被起诉了 总得有人承担责任
That's how a bank works.
银行就是这样的地方
-However… -Who is in charge of Morozumi Industry?
-可是… -负责诸角产业的人
You, right?
是你吧？
Yes.
是
Sooner the better.
越快越好
Bring the letter of resignation tomorrow.
明早就提交辞职信吧
By the way,
对了
this is voluntary.
这都是你自己的意思哦
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NIHONBASHI BRANCH
（东京第一银行日本桥分行）
Ms. Kitahara.
北原小姐
I wanted to apologize for what I said.
今天发生的事 真对不起
I shouldn't have said that.
我不应该那样说的
I am sorry for making blind assumptions.
我擅自把你说成那样 真是抱歉
What were you trying to say to me that time, Ms. Kitahara?
其实你那时候想对我说什么吧？
You were about to say something.
欲言又止的
After you said that I didn't know anything.
你说我们什么都不懂 之后想说什么？
Ever since I became a branch inspector,
自从我开始做分行稽核工作
I've met many people who suffer because of
我就遇到了很多因为银行老套的作风
the old-fashioned mindset of the bank and its
以及自大无理的上司
unreasonable managers.
而受苦的职员
They can't say what they want to say,
他们不能畅所欲言
and they suffer alone.
独自受苦
If you're experiencing that right now,
如果你现在也有那样的感觉的话
I won't keep quiet.
我不会袖手旁观的
It was not to improve my performance.
那不是为了业绩
It was an order.
而是命令
What?
什么？
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
Today's sardine is delicious.
今天的鱼煮得太好吃了吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Mai is not home yet.
小舞今天真晚啊
What's wrong?
怎么了吗？
Nothing.
没事
-Mr. Soma. -Yes?
-相马 -是
Is Mai doing unnecessary things and causing you trouble?
该不会小舞那家伙又招惹了什么事 给你找麻烦了吧？
No.
没有
That's a "yes."
那就是有
I told
我…
Mr. Morozumi that the principal was guaranteed.
对诸角社长说了可以保证本金
It was an order from the Manager.
因为那是桥爪经理的命令
How did it happen?
怎么回事？
Don't you want to be number one this year?
你们今年不想争第一了吗？
You want it, right?
都想当第一吧？
Yes!
-是
All we need is higher numbers. Your job is to
只要数字冲上去就可以了 而你们的工作
enhance your performance.
就是提升业绩
Is that clear?
都明白了吗？
Yes.
-是
-Kitahara. -Yes.
-北原
How is the investment trust?
之前的投资信托怎么样了？
I am sorry,
很抱歉
but Mr. Morozumi won't agree to it that easily.
诸角先生那边还没有答应
I see. Tell him that the principal is guaranteed.
是吗？那只要说会保证本金就好了
-What? -He will buy it then.
-什么？ -这么说 他们就会买了
But if there's a loss--
但要是有什么损失的话…
No worries.
没事的
There won't be a loss of principal in this economy.
按现在这市场行情 不会有亏损的
However…
可是…
I will take responsibility if there is any problem.
万一有问题 我会负责
Make sure to bring in the results.
必须做出个结果来
This is an order by the Branch Manager.
这是分行经理的命令
Yes, sir.
是
Investment trust is risky.
投资信托有风险啊
For this trust, the principal is guaranteed.
不会的 我们能保证本金
You mean I won't lose?
你的意思是不会亏钱？
That's right.
没错
That sounds really great.
那听起来不错啊
I didn't know that.
我都不知道呢
I was hoping that it would work out,
我一直祈祷一切会顺利
and not cause him any loss.
不会造成亏损
But the result was awful.
却得到了最糟糕的结果
It is only a loss of three million yen.
不就损失了三百万吗？
It's his fault for redeeming it at a time like this.
只能怪他在这个时期解约
I will go apologize to him.
我去跟诸角社长道歉
No you won't.
不行
If you apologize, you will be admitting that it's our fault.
道歉不就表示是我们错了吗？
What should I do?
那我该怎么做？
Just say that you never
你就说你没说过
guaranteed the principal.
可以保证本金就可以了
But you told me to say the principal was guaranteed
但那时是你要我说能保住本金
and that you'd take responsibility if there were any problems.
还说万一有什么问题 你会承担责任
What? I didn't say such a thing.
什么？我可没说过那样的话
You did this on your own.
是你自己擅自做主的吧？
No…
我…
Never admit what you did, got it?
你别承认就对了 懂了吗？
If you want to continue working here, that's your only choice.
你要是想继续在这里工作的话 就必须这么做
Do you understand?
懂了吧？
Yes, sir.
是
No.
不
I didn't say that the principal was guaranteed.
我没有说过能保证本金
Give me a break!
开什么玩笑？
Look at my diary here.
你看看这个
Read what you told me.
你看看那时你跟我说了什么
Hey!
喂
I see. So that's what happened.
原来如此
I've been regretting what I had said.
我很后悔说了那样的话
Branch Manager came to me and said that
刚才桥爪经理找我
I should resign.
要我辞职
What?
什么？
Write a letter of resignation.
你主动辞职吧
That's awful!
太过分了
He's placing all the blame on you. That's not fair.
他居然让你一个人承担责任 真不可理喻
But there is no evidence that he ordered me.
但是没有证据证明是他的命令
He knew that from the beginning.
他从一开始就计划好了
But your colleagues will understand…
但分行的人应该都知道啊
No way.
没用的
Why?
为什么？
Branch Manager is the "rule" in our branch.
在我们这里 一切都听经理的
That's why whenever there was a problem,
所以一旦谁出了问题
I always thought that it might have been ordered by the Branch Manager.
我们都清楚是被桥爪经理指使的
But I turned a blind eye.
只是大家都视而不见
I was relieved that it wasn't me.
内心庆幸不是自己出事
Since you work for a Branch Manager like him,
在那种经理底下工作
I understand why you kept silent, and never said what you wanted to say.
我也明白你为什么有苦说不出了
-But… -I…
-但是… -我…
I think I had forgotten the most important thing.
我想我忘了最重要的东西
Even if I was pushed into a corner, I had no right to deceive a customer.
就算我被逼到墙角 也不能欺骗客户
This bank is rotten.
这家银行已经败坏了
Even an elementary school student can tell that this is wrong.
连小学生都知道这样做是不对的
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
When I got a job offer at Tokyo Daiichi Bank,
我当初收到 东京第一银行的入职通知时
I was so happy.
我真的非常开心
I am from a small town,
我家是个乡下小地方
so everyone got excited that I would be working at a bank.
所以大家都为我 能在银行工作感到兴奋
My parents were happy too.
爸妈也非常高兴
I felt like I was able to make my parents really proud.
我第一次觉得自己尽了孝心
I don't have any special talent,
我没什么出众的才能
but this employee ID gave me confidence and a place to belong.
但这个员工证件 给我带来了自信和归属
I was hoping to keep working here.
我曾想过一辈子都在这里工作
I didn't want to resign.
我不想辞职
I didn't want to resign, but…
我真的不想辞职
Maybe because her mother passed away when she was young,
可能因为她妈妈走得早吧
she always pretended to be fine even when she was sick,
小时候开始 不论是肚子痛 发烧 还是学校有事
had a problem at school,
甚至是被男友甩的时候
or when she was dumped by her boyfriend.
她都装作没事
Here you go.
给你
But when it concerns other people,
但关系到其他人的时候
she can't ignore it and has to speak up.
她就不能容忍 替对方出头
That's a problem.
真是伤脑筋啊
But sometimes I think…
但我有时会想啊
Yes?
嗯？
When I have no one on my side,
在我孤身一人的时候
if a person like Hanasaki is with me,
如果有像花琦这样的家伙在身边的话
I will probably feel at ease.
应该会变得轻松一些吧
I am frustrated.
我不甘心
I…
我…
I am so frustrated.
真的非常不甘心
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
Hey.
喂
Good evening.
辛苦了
Hey, look at your face.
你那什么表情啊？
Mr. Soma.
相马
I can't forgive that Branch Manager.
我无法原谅那个桥爪经理
So you went to see Ms. Kitahara, huh?
你果然是去见北原了
Yes.
对
I see, so that's what happened.
原来如此啊
It's not fair
这样
that Ms. Kitahara has to take responsibility for everything.
只让她一个人承担责任 真是太不公平了
I will see him tomorrow.
我明天就去找他…
Don't.
不行
You won't stand a chance against him without any evidence.
你没证据指证他 根本斗不过他的
A sentimental argument won't work with him.
他可不是你动之以情就能说服的人
In fact, he'll end up cornering Ms. Kitahara even more
相反的 说不定因为你
for telling you everything.
北原的处境会更难堪
Then I should find evidence to prove that he ordered it.
那我只要找到证据 证明是他的命令不就好了？
There is no evidence. It'll end up being a battle of
就是没证据啊 到头来就是
"he said she said."
各说各话
Maybe you are right. But…
可能吧 不过…
But I heard from Ms. Kitahara that…
我刚才听北原说
That's why whenever there was a problem,
所以一旦谁出了问题
I always thought that it might have been ordered by the Branch Manager.
我们都清楚是被经理指使的
There should be more people who had to obey his orders.
应该还有其他 被桥爪经理强制命令做事的人
Don't tell me that
你别告诉我
you will ask everyone in the branch.
你要去找分行的每个人问一遍啊
I can't turn a blind eye.
我无法坐视不管啊
Stop it. They won't tell you anything.
算了吧 他们不可能跟你说实话的
If they know about Ms. Kitahara…
如果他们知道北原现在的处境…
Even if do, they'll be too busy trying to protect themselves.
就算知道 也忙着自保吧？
But it's not right that they have to do things that are wrong just because
可是明知道是错的 却因为是经理的命令而不得不做
it's his order.
这是不对的啊
Listen Hanasaki. Let me repeat this.
听好了 花琦 我再说一次
A sound argument is not always accepted in the world of banking.
银行这地方就不是个讲理的世界 不
In fact, it's not accepted most of the time.
应该说不讲理的情况更多
You will meet many people
我们会遇到许多在各个分行
who suffer unreasonable treatment within the branch.
被刁难而感到痛苦的人们
You can't be emotionally involved with every single person you meet.
我们没办法对他们每个人都注入感情
If you want to work in a bank,
你如果还想在银行干下去的话
you have to learn to ignore and bear certain things.
就少管闲事 好好学着怎么去忍耐
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
（辞职信）
Excuse me. I am Hanasaki of the Branch Inspection.
不好意思 我是分行稽核班的花琦
May I ask you something?
我能不能问你一些事情？
No, Branch Manager has not given me any unreasonable orders.
没有 桥爪经理不曾给过我不合理的指令
How about someone else?
那其他人呢？
Do you know anyone who suffers--
你知不知道有谁被他…
I don't know anything.
我什么都不知道
Can I go?
我可以走了吧？
I don't know.
不知道
But it could happen to someone else.
但再这样下去的话 可能会有其他人遭遇到同样的事
I really don't know anything.
我们真的什么都不知道
Mr. Nakamura, you may know something.
中村课长 你一定知道些什么的
Ms. Hanasaki, do you know what you are trying to do?
花琦小姐 你知道你现在到底在做什么吗？
I want to stand by Ms. Kitahara and everyone in this branch.
我想成为北原和分行各位同仁的伙伴
A bank is not as simple as you think.
银行并不是你想的那么简单
-Excuse me. I am Hanasaki-- -What are you doing?
-不好意思 我是… -你到底在干嘛？
Why do you always go off by yourself?
你怎么又乱来了？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
But you understand now that there is nothing we can do, right?
不过 现在你懂了吧？ 我们什么也做不了
Yes.
是
Don't visit the Nihonbashi Branch anymore
从现在开始 别再去日本桥分行
and don't go out all day today.
而且今天一整天禁止外出
I have manager training so I can't keep watch over you.
我要去上主任研修课程 没办法监视你
But don't go anywhere. Understand?
但你绝对不准再乱跑 听懂了吗？
Yes.
是
Excuse me.
打扰了
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
（辞职信）
What is it?
怎么了吗？
Nothing.
没事
TOUICHI HASHIZUME
（桥爪藤一）
AOYAMA BRANCH MANAGER NIHONBASHI BRANCH MANAGER
（日本桥分行经理）
BRANCH OFFICE LIST
（分行名单）
NIHONBASHI BRANCH
（日本桥分行）
RETIRED EMPLOYEE
（离职者）
TRANSFERRED EMPLOYEE TEMPORARILY TRANSFERRED EMPLOYEE
（调职者 派驻者）
SEARCH
（搜寻）
TEMPORARY TRANSFER
（暂时调职）
RETIRED
（已离职）
I'm finally done.
总算结束了
TEMPORARY TRANSFER
（暂时调职）
Damn her…
那家伙
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NIHONBASHI BRANCH
（东京第一银行日本桥分行）
Ms. Kitahara will be leaving the company for personal reasons.
北原从今天起将因个人原因而离职
She will say goodbye to everyone.
和大家道别吧
Um…
那个…
Thank you for everything.
感谢大家一直以来的照顾
Please wait.
请等一下
What are you doing?
你做什么？
It is unfair for Ms. Kitahara to resign.
北原小姐如果辞职 就太不公平了
I told you not to come back to this branch.
我不是说过 禁止你再踏入我们分行了吗？
Ms. Hanasaki, go back.
花琦小姐 请你回去
Mr. Hashizume.
桥爪经理
Why does Ms. Kitahara have to leave?
为什么北原小姐非辞职不可呢？
She wrote a resignation letter of her own will, to take responsibility
他为了负起 与诸角产业产生纠纷的责任
for the trouble with Mr. Morozumi.
而提出了辞呈
However,
但是
it was you who ordered her to say that the principal was guaranteed.
是你命令他告诉对方能保全本金的 不是吗？
Are you insane?
你在胡说些什么？
I never said such a thing.
我怎么可能说出那那种话？
I heard it from Ms. Kitahara.
北原小姐全告诉我了
In order to become the nation's number one branch,
你为了使分行 在业绩表扬中拿到全国第一
you ordered her to sell investment funds by lying to the customer
指使他欺骗客户 贩卖投资信托
to produce results.
强迫部下把业绩拿出来
You're very rude. Never have I
你真是太失礼了 我从来没有
forced my employees to do something dishonest.
强迫过部下做出不正当的行为
This is the list of the people who have been transferred or retired
这是桥爪经理你来到这里的两年间
from this branch since you became the Branch Manager two years ago.
分行所有被调职及离职的行员名单
I met and interviewed them.
我已经与这些人面谈过了
They were not willing to tell me anything.
但他们都不太敢告诉我真相
However…
不过
Do you remember Mr. Yuichi Anzai who was in Public Relations a year ago?
你还记得一年前曾在涉外课 工作过的安西优一吧？
Mr. Anzai said that Mr. Hashizume ordered him
他说桥爪经理曾命令他
to sell the investment trust
欺骗客户说一定能够赚钱
by lying to the customers and guaranteeing a profit.
从而贩卖投资信托
TEMPORARY TRANSFER TOKYO FIRST SCIENCE INC.
（暂时调职东京第一科学公司）
When Mr. Anzai refused to do so,
安西拒绝了这个命令
he was transferred to another company.
却被调往别的公司
He told me so.
他是这样告诉我的
That's not true.
简直是胡说
-Well-- -No one will believe you.
-可是… -根本不会有人相信你
What do you all think?
你们觉得呢？
Do you believe her?
你们相信吗？
As you can see…
你看吧
Excuse me.
不好意思
Mr. Soma.
相马
I believe her.
我相信她
What are you doing?
你们搞什么啊？
I am sorry,
非常抱歉
but two people including Ms. Kitahara are
但因为包含北原小姐在内
testifying the same thing.
有两个人都提出同样的证言
How can the Branch Inspector know anything?
你们分行稽核班懂什么啊？
It seems like you are assuming that I ordered them to do it, but where's
你们一口咬定是我提出那种命令
the evidence?
证据呢？
Show me the evidence.
有的话 就拿出来看看啊
-Ms. Kitahara and Mr. Anzai are testify-- -But...
-北原小姐和安西先生的证言… -所以嘛
The testimony of two measly bankers doesn't mean anything.
光靠这两个行员的证言 根本没有任何意义
She's blaming someone else for something she did on her own.
这家伙根本是把自己犯下的错 让别人来背黑锅
I am quite annoyed.
这对我来说非常困扰啊
With all due respect…
请恕我直言
It is you, Mr. Hashizume,
让别人来背黑锅的
who is blaming others.
是你 桥爪经理
What?
你说什么？
You use your position as Branch Manager
你利用自己身为分行经理的地位
and treat your subordinates as pawns.
将部下当作棋子来操纵
You're forcing them to do bad things.
逼他们做出不法事情的人是你
-Shut up! -No, I won't.
-住嘴 -我不要
You deceive customers without dirtying your hands
你不弄脏自己的手 欺骗客户
and place all the blame on your subordinates. That's wrong!
然后要部下当你的替罪羔羊 这是大错特错
You said this nation's number one branch
你说这是全国第一的分行
was different from the others.
与其他分行是完全不同的
This branch may have an award for being number one,
但即便这间分行 有第一名的表扬奖状
but it does not have heart.
却没有心
Branch Manager Hashizume, you're the one taking the heart away.
而你 桥爪经理 就是把心夺走的那个人
Um…
那个…
I was turning a blind eye.
其实是我对这坐视不管
One year ago, as well as this time,
一年前是这样 这次也是
Mr. Hashizume ordered Mr. Anzai and Ms. Kitahara to act dishonestly.
桥爪经理对安西和北原 都下了不当的指示
-Nakamura… damn you-- -I…
-中村 你这家伙 -我…
I was ordered by the Branch Manager to
我也曾受过桥爪经理指使
process a loan by making the interest rates seem advantageous.
谎报利率 好多签几个贷款回来
Tanaka.
田中
I'm being ordered to give Asagi Products a higher loan than what's required.
他也命令我让麻木物产 进行不必要的融资
Ms. Kitahara isn't the only one being forced to do wrong by the Branch Manager.
被桥爪经理强迫的人并不只有北原
-Fujiwara. -I'm being forced as well.
-藤原 -我也有被指使过
Me too.
我也是
He ordered me, too.
他也命令过我
I guess there are more than just two measly people.
看来不只区区两个人呢
Mr. Hashizume,
桥爪经理
it will be impossible to ignore all these voices as meaningless.
你不可能还说 这些声音没有任何意义了吧？
Morozumi Industry withdrew the lawsuit.
诸角产业公司好像撤销了诉讼
We paid compensation to settle the case out of court.
我们支付了和解金 达成了和解
We prevented it from getting serious.
避免事情闹得更大
Branch Inspection did a great job.
这可是分行稽核班的功劳
But I can't get too happy about it.
不过 很难让我高兴起来
Yes?
怎么了？
Mr. Hashizume has been transferred.
桥爪经理被调职了
They didn't fire him to prevent the problem from becoming public knowledge.
他没有被解雇 也是为了避免事情被公开 对吧？
I see. You are moving to Tategawa Branch.
这样啊 你要去馆川分行吗？
Yes.
是的
Everyone at the Nihonbashi Branch advised me to stay
日本桥分行的同事都要我留下来
and work to take responsibility.
好好工作 负起责任
I'm sure it will be tough,
一定很辛苦吧？
but I wish you the best.
但请你务必加油喔！
Thank you.
好 谢谢你
This bank may be rotten, but the people working in it are not.
或许这间银行已经败坏了 但在这里工作的人却没有堕落
You taught me that, Ms. Hanasaki.
这是你教会我的 花琦小姐
I will start all over again from the bottom. At this bank.
我会在这间银行从头开始努力的
Thank you very much, Ms. Hanasaki.
真的很谢谢你 花琦小姐
I didn't do much.
不客气
Bye.
再见
Mr. Soma.
相马
Do you remember what I said to Executive Director Shindo a year ago?
你还记得一年前 我和真藤常务说过什么吗？
This bank is full of wrong things.
这家银行尽是些不法的勾当
What should we do then?
那我们该怎么做呢？
I think we should change.
我认为我们应该要改变
I was arrogant to think that I could change the bank.
我居然还自以为是地说要改变银行呢
After a year, nothing has changed.
现在一年过去了 什么都没有改变
What's wrong? Are you ready to give up?
怎么了？你要投降了吗？
-No. -Then what?
-不是 -那不然呢？
I may be able to change the people who work here.
我或许可以改变在这里工作的人们
I may be able to ask them to change.
应该说 或许可以让他们改变
If more people make changes,
只要越来越多人做出改变
then the bank may change someday.
总有一天 这间银行也会不一样吧？
We've still got a long way to go.
不过 这可是漫漫长路呢
-I see. -Yes!
-这样啊 -没错
-It's time. Let's go. -Okay.
-都已经这个时候了 走吧 -好
Today, we are going to Tsukishima.
今天我们要去的是月岛分行
That's right.
是的
So, Executive Director Shindo settled everything amicably?
也就是说 是靠真藤常务 平息了这这件事 是吗？
I guess he didn't want to taint his faction.
大概是不想让自己的派系有污点吧？
I see.
原来如此
He's got a rival now,
真藤现在有对手了
so Mr. Shindo must be feeling anxious.
也该焦急了吧？
A rival?
对手？
Mr. Doujima returned from New York.
堂岛先生从纽约回来了
What? Is it that Mr. Doujima?
什么？是那位堂岛先生吗？
Yes. He returns as a Senior Executive Director.
是的 他会以专务董事的身分回来
SENIOR EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR SHOGO DOUJIMA
（专务董事 堂岛正吾）
Mr. Shindo.
真藤
Long time no see.
好久不见
Senior Executive Director Doujima.
堂岛专务 好久不见
I hear you've been working hard under President Serizawa.
听说你在芹泽行长麾下 似乎非常活跃呢
Oh, no.
过奖了
I hear that you covered up a scandal in a branch the other day.
前几天发生在分行的那个烂摊子 你都收拾好了吧？
It was really a small thing.
不过是件小案子
I see.
这样啊
But Mr. Shindo…
不过 真藤啊
You won't be able to do as you like
接下来可不会再让你
from now on.
任意妄为了
Mr. Shindo. Regarding the meeting with Mr. Itami from Itami Group,
真藤常务 关于与伊丹集团的伊丹会长会谈一事
how about next Wednesday?
排定下周三是否妥当？
PERSONNEL NOTICE
（人事调动通知）
Damn Branch Inspectors…
分行稽核班那班人
doing unnecessary things.
真是多管闲事
Where do you want to go for lunch?
今天午餐要吃什么好呢？
Monja is famous in Tsukishima.
月岛的话 当然就要吃文字烧啊
Sounds nice.
听起来不错
Believe it or not, there is a hamburger shop too.
这里居然有间看起来不错吃的汉堡店
Nice!
也可以啊
Urchin beef roll…
海胆牛肉卷
Urchin?
海胆？
Let's go.
走吧
Hello, I'm Matsuki.
你好 我是松木
This is fate.
只能说是命运了
Yes!
太棒了
I'll terminate the loan. It's final.
给我终止贷款 那是最后期限
That's withdrawal of loan credit.
你这样是恶意回收贷款吧？
I may have reached my limit.
或许已经到尽头了吧？
That's unacceptable.
真是岂有此理
Please withdraw the debt recovery!
请撤回回收融资的决定